onelegal.com 2018-11-25

# Privacy Policy | One Legal

### Privacy Policy

One Legal is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy sets out how we collect, store, process, transfer, share, and use data that identifies or is associated with you (“personal information”) and information regarding our use of cookies and similar technologies.

#### 1\. Personal information we collect about you and how we use it

**1.1.** **Information you give to use:** We collect personal information about you when you voluntarily submit information directly to us by filling in forms on our website or by corresponding with us by phone, email, or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our website, subscribe to the One Legal service, enter a competition, promotion or survey and when you report a problem with our website, or use some other feature of the One Legal service as available from time to time. The table at Annex 1 sets out the categories of personal information you provide to us.

**1.2.** **Information we receive from other sources:** We may receive personal information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide from time to time. We also work closely with third parties (including, for example, subcontractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them, subject to your agreements with them.

**1.3.** We also automatically collect personal information about you indirectly about how you access and use the One Legal service and information about the device you use to access the One Legal service. This information includes device ID or unique identifier; device type, geolocation info; computer and connection information. We also collect personal information using cookies, web beacons and similar technologies about the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take on our services, within our advertising or e-mail content. The table at Annex 2 sets out the categories of personal information we collect automatically.

**1.4.** We may supplement the personal information we collect with information from third parties and add it to your account information. For example, we may collect and use demographic information that is publicly available, additional contact information, credit check information, and information from credit bureaus, as allowed by applicable national laws

**1.5.** We may link or combine the personal information we collect and/or receive about you and the information we collect automatically. This allows us to provide you with a personalized experience regardless of how you interact with us.

**1.6.** We may anonymize and aggregate any of the personal information we collect (so that you are not personally identified). We may use anonymized information for purposes that include testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving the One Legal service and developing new products and features. We may also share such anonymized information with others.

#### 2\. Disclosure of your personal information

**2.1.** We have never shared your personal information with third parties, and have no plans to do so, except:

**2.1.1.** If your request it;

**2.1.2.** to complete a transaction initiated by you (which may sometimes include disclosure to a credit card bureau); or

**2.1.3.** if we are required or allowed by the law, such as to respond to a subpoena or to investigate fraudulent activity.

**2.2.** To further protect your confidentiality, we require any organizations to which we provide data to have similar privacy safeguards and contractually only allow them to use our customers’ information for the intended service. You do not have to ask for this confidentiality, it is our standard practice.

**2.3.** If, in the future, we ever decide that it would be in your interest to share your personal information for any other purpose, you will be informed in advance, and given the opportunity to opt out.

**2.4.** **Publicly accessible blogs.** Our website includes publicly accessible blogs or community forums. Any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected and used by others who access them. This includes information posted on our public social media accounts. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@onelegal.com](mailto:privacy@onelegal.com).

**2.5.** **Testimonials.** With your consent, we may display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site, along with other endorsements. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@onelegal.com](mailto:privacy@onelegal.com).

#### 3\. Marketing and advertising

**3.1.** From time to time we may contact you with relevant information about the One Legal service and our other products and services. Most messages will be sent electronically. For some messages, we may use personal information we collect about you to help us determine the most relevant information to share with you.

**3.2.** If you do not want to receive such messages from us, you will be able to tell us by selecting certain boxes on forms we use when we first collect your contact details. You can also change your marketing preferences at any time by following the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails.

#### 4\. Storing and transferring your personal information

**4.1.** **Security.** All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers in a controlled environment with limited access. Any payment transactions will be encrypted in transit using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our service, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. Subscribers should not share their password with anyone.

**4.2.** While no transmission of information via the internet is completely secure, we take reasonable measures to protect your personal information. We cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

**4.3.** **International transfers of your personal information.** The personal information we collect may be transferred to and stored in countries outside of the jurisdiction you are in where we and our third-party service providers have operations. If you are located in the European Union (“EU”), your personal information will be processed outside of the EU including in the United States; these international transfers of your personal information are made pursuant to appropriate safeguards, such as standard data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission. If you wish to enquire further about these safeguards used, please contact us using the details set out at the end of this privacy policy.

#### 5\. Retaining your information

**5.1.** We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of our legitimate business interests and satisfying any legal or reporting requirements. In addition, we may retain personal information from closed accounts to comply with national laws, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our User Agreement and take other actions permitted or required by applicable national laws. After it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we dispose of it in a secure manner according to our data retention and deletion policies.

**5.2.** To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we process your personal information and the applicable legal requirements.

#### 6\. Referral program

**6.1.** We operate a referral program for our service; you may choose to provide us with names and email addresses of individuals who you feel would be interested in learning more about our products and services in exchange for rewards. We will store the contact details for the minimum time necessary to track the success of our referral service. The referred individual may request that their contact details be removed from our database and they may also contact us at any time at [privacy@onelegal.com](mailto:privacy@onelegal.com) to make the request.

#### 7\. Your rights in respect of your personal information

**7.1.** In accordance with applicable privacy law, you have the following rights in respect of your personal information that we hold:

**7.1.1.** **Right of access and portability.** The right to access your personal information and to receive that personal information in a commonly used format and to have it ported to another data controller.

**7.1.2.** **Right to rectification.** The right to rectify your personal information without undue delay where that personal information is inaccurate or incomplete.

**7.1.3.** **Right to erasure.** The right to have your personal information erased without undue delay in certain circumstances, such as where the personal information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed.

**7.1.4.** **Right to restriction.** The right to restrict the processing undertaken by us on your personal information in certain circumstances, such as where we send marketing communications, or where the accuracy of the personal information is contested by you, for a period enabling us to verify the accuracy of that personal information.

**7.1.5.** **Right to object.** The right to object, on grounds relating to your situation, to the processing of your personal information, and to object to the processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes, by us or by third parties, to the extent it is related to such direct marketing.

**7.1.6.** **Right to close your account.** The right to request that we close your account.

**7.2.** If you wish to exercise one of these rights, please contact us using the contact details at the end of this privacy policy. Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct or request deletion of your personal information by contacting us at a href=mailto:privacy@onelegal.com>privacy@onelegal.com. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

**7.3.** If you reside in the European Union (EU), One Legal is the controller of your personal information for purposes of European data protection legislation. You also have the right to lodge a complaint to your local data protection authority. Information about how to contact your local data protection authority is available at [ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080).

#### 8\. Cookies and similar technologies

**8.1.** Our Service uses cookies and similar technologies (collectively referred to as cookies) to distinguish you from other users of our service. This helps us to provide you with a good service. This helps us enhance and personalize your user experience, to monitor and improve our website and services, and for other internal purposes. As is true of most websites, we gather certain personal information automatically.

**8.2.** We use the following types of cookies:

**8.2.1.** **Strictly necessary cookies.** These cookies are required for the essential operation of our Service such as to authenticate you and prevent fraudulent use.

**8.2.2.** **Analytical/performance cookies.** These cookies allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our Service when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our Service works, for example, by ensuring that you can find information easily.

**8.2.3.** **Functionality cookies.** These cookies are used to recognize you when you return to our Service. This enables us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

**8.2.3.** **Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your visit to our Service, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our Service and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

**8.3.** Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

**8.4.** We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used to serve you interest-based ads, you may opt-out at any time by clearing your browser cookies. Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**8.5.** Although most web browsers automatically accept cookies, some browsers’ settings can be modified to decline cookies or alert you when a website is attempting to place a cookie on your computer. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including strictly necessary cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.

**8.6.** **Social Media.** Our website includes social media features, such as Facebook Like button and widgets such as the Share button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are hosted on our site or by a third party, and your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

#### 9\. Links to third party websites

**9.1.** The One Legal service may, from time to time, contain links to and from third party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check the individual policies before you submit any information to those websites.

**9.2.** Some of the pages on our website may utilize framing techniques to serve content to/from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our website. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to One Legal.

#### 10\. Our policy towards children

**10.1.** The One Legal service is not directed at persons under 16 and we do not intend to collect personal information from children under 16 in our capacity as a controller. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information without appropriate consent, then please contact us using the details below so that we can take the appropriate steps in accordance with our legal obligations and this privacy policy.

#### 11\. Changes to this policy

**11.1.** We may update this privacy policy from time to time and so you should review this page periodically. When we change this privacy policy in a material way, we will update the “last modified” date at the end of this privacy policy. Changes to this privacy policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

#### 12\. Notice to you

**12.1.** If we need to provide you with information about something, whether for legal, marketing or other business related purposes, we will select what we believe is the best way to get in contact with you. We will usually do this through email or by placing a notice on our website. The fact that we may send notices to you will not stop you from being able to opt out of certain types of contact as described in this privacy policy.

#### 13\. Contacting us

**13.1.** Regardless of your location, any questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcome and should be addressed to our Data Protection Officer, Josh Hanft (Director of Information Technology) at [privacy@onelegal.com](mailto:privacy@onelegal.com). Communication can also be addressed to:

One Legal LLC

1400 N. McDowell Blvd, Suite 300

Petaluma, CA, 94954

United States of America

**13.2.** This policy was last modified on May 23, 2018

#### Annex 1: Personal information we collect

#### Annex 2: Personal information we collect automatically
